<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Minimal 3DP</title><link>https://minimal3dp.com/blog/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Minimal 3DP</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://minimal3dp.com/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>This Week on Minimal 3DP (April 28)</title><link>https://minimal3dp.com/blog/2024/04/28/this-week-on-minimal-3dp-april-28/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://minimal3dp.com/blog/2024/04/28/this-week-on-minimal-3dp-april-28/</guid><description>OrcaSlicer Logo Photo: SoftFever The Week of April 28st 2024 I am currently working on several projects this week. They include:
Voron 2.4 R2 Pro+ Build Orca Slicer Seam Settings STEM Outreach Voron 2.4 R2 Pro+ Build i recordedcan unboxing video on Sunday and I have begun building the Voron this week. I am working myvway through the assembly manual and wiol drop a vireo of rrame assembly next weekend.</description></item><item><title>This Week on Minimal 3DP (April 21)</title><link>https://minimal3dp.com/blog/2024/04/21/this-week-on-minimal-3dp-april-21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://minimal3dp.com/blog/2024/04/21/this-week-on-minimal-3dp-april-21/</guid><description>Voron Circuit Board Logo Photo: Team FDM The Week of April 21st 2024 I am currently working on several projects this week. They include:
Voron 2.4 R2 Pro+ Build Belt Driven Ender 3 STEM Outreach Voron 2.4 R2 Pro+ Build I have started getting together my project website for my Voron build. One of the newer ideas I am trying is to create a project website. I am hoping that it makes it easier for me to save references and other links.</description></item><item><title>Klipper Calibration Website</title><link>https://minimal3dp.com/blog/2024/04/10/klipper-calibration-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://minimal3dp.com/blog/2024/04/10/klipper-calibration-website/</guid><description>Klipper Calibration M3DP Tools and Connections Photo: Mike Wilson / CC-BY-CA A while ago, I create the my Klipper Calibration Spreadsheet to help myself keep track of and remember various Klipper formulas to tune and improve my 3D prints. I decided to share the tools and i have received lots of requests to share the Spreadsheet. Rather than giving everyone access to edit my original sheet, I have recommended to everyone to &amp;ldquo;Make a Copy&amp;rdquo; of the sheet for their personal use.</description></item></channel></rss>