<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Builds on Minimal 3DP</title><link>https://minimal3dp.com/categories/builds/</link><description>Recent content in Builds on Minimal 3DP</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 20:54:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://minimal3dp.com/categories/builds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Voron 2.4 R2 Pro+ Build References</title><link>https://minimal3dp.com/projects/journal/voron-2.4-r2/voron-build-references/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://minimal3dp.com/projects/journal/voron-2.4-r2/voron-build-references/</guid><description>Build references and links for the Voron 2.4 R2 Pro+ FormBot kit. I needed a centralized location for all the reference material I need to build the 3D printer.
References and Links Kit Kit on AliExpress: Voron 2.4 V2.4 R2 Pro+ Latest Version Best Quality CoreXY 3D Printer Kit) FormBot Site: Voron Kit Voron Refs Voron 2.4 Website 2.4 Manual Voron 2.4 GitHub FormBot References: Wiring Diagram Wiring Instruction for Voron 2.</description></item><item><title>Voron 2.4 R2 Pro+ Build Parts List</title><link>https://minimal3dp.com/projects/journal/voron-2.4-r2/voron-build-parts-list/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://minimal3dp.com/projects/journal/voron-2.4-r2/voron-build-parts-list/</guid><description> Parts List for the Voron 2.4 R2 Pro+ FormBot kit. I will show the parts list from FrormBot but at the end of the page I will include my cross-checks.
Parts List from FormBot Kit Kit on AliExpress: Voron 2.4 V2.4 R2 Pro+ Latest Version Best Quality CoreXY 3D Printer Kit) FormBot Site: Voron Kit FormBot Parts FormBot Parts List FormBot Parts List Photo: Various Sources M3DP Parts List (Updated as I use Parts) Frame M5 x 16 BHCS 10 A Extrusions 4 B Extrusions 2 C Extrusions 1 D Extrusion 1 E Extrusion 4 Corner Brackets</description></item><item><title>Voron 2.4 R2 Pro+ Build - Building the Frame</title><link>https://minimal3dp.com/projects/journal/voron-2.4-r2/voron-build-frame/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://minimal3dp.com/projects/journal/voron-2.4-r2/voron-build-frame/</guid><description> In this section, I will be building the frame of my Voron 2.4 R2 Kit
References and Links
Voron 2.4 R2 Manual Build Steps The Voron assembly manual starts with the building of the frame. I will start from this point.
Blind Joints Voron Build Guide - Blind Joints Photo: Various Frame Using the blind joints. The Frame is assembled.
Frame Parts M5 x 16 BHCS 10 A Extrusions 4 B Extrusions 2 C Extrusions 1 D Extrusion 1 E Extrusion 4 Corner Brackets Assembled Frame Photo: Various</description></item></channel></rss>